wescom.org 2007-08-23

# Wescom Privacy Policy

| 

## Introduction

Wescom Central Credit Union, herein referred to as “Wescom Credit Union”, is a member-owned financial cooperative. You joined Wescom Credit Union with the expectation that we act in the best interest of our membership and make available the financial products and services that enable you to meet your financial goals. Trust is the foundation of our relationship with you, and the preservation of that trust is of the highest importance to us. It is with that purpose in mind that we have formulated our privacy policy. Wescom Credit Union; Wescom Financial Services, LLC ("WFS"); and Wescom Insurance Services, LLC ("WIS") all want you to understand what information we collect, how we use it, and with whom we share it. We will inform you annually about our privacy policy.

This joint policy applies to both current and former Wescom members, and addresses the disclosure of personal information about you that may not be available in public records. We use the terms "affiliate" and "non-affiliate" to describe companies with which we may share your information. An "affiliate" is one which either Wescom Credit Union, WFS, or WIS directly or indirectly owns or over which we have control. As WFS and WIS are indirectly controlled by Wescom Credit Union, WFS, and WIS are affiliates of each other. A "non-affiliate" is a third party with whom we may have a business or marketing relationship and who may perform services on our or your behalf.

## What Information We Collect

We collect personal information directly from you in the course of providing you our products and services. We collect your personal information from you, your applications, your transactions with us and with non-affiliated third parties, consumer reporting agencies, and by verifying your information. The type of information we collect is about your identity (name, address, date of birth, driver's license number, social security number); your transaction history with us, our affiliates, or others (account balances, payment history, credit card usage); and your assets, income and creditworthiness. We collect your personal information in order to provide you with products and services you request; to know who you are and prevent unauthorized access to your information; to offer products and services that are of value to you; and to comply with the regulations that govern us.

## What Information We Disclose

We will not sell, share, give or otherwise provide your personal information to any non-affiliated third party for the marketing of their products and services. We may share your personal information as described above with our affiliates and in accordance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act referred to below. In addition, we may offer to our members the products and services of a non-affiliated third party, but Wescom Credit Union, WFS, and/or WIS will market those products and services directly to you. We will not provide the non-affiliated third party with information about you unless you request it or initiate a transaction. We choose our third party service providers carefully and enter into contractual agreements with them to ensure that the information you give directly to them is used only to provide you with the service you requested. In accordance with our contractual agreements, third parties may not use any of the information we provide to them to market their products or services directly to you.

We are permitted by law to share any of the information we collect with non-affiliated third parties to administer the products and services we provide, to follow your instructions, to meet our business needs, or to comply with state and federal law. You cannot opt out of the disclosure of this information. Examples of these third parties are financial service providers such as financial advisors, securities broker-dealers, and insurance companies and agents; non-financial service providers such as credit bureaus, check printers, mail houses, marketing service providers; and others such as courts and state and federal government agencies. In addition, we may also disclose information about you to other non-affiliated third parties not described in this policy as permitted or required by law. Please be assured that we will only share information with non-affiliated third parties to the extent required or permitted by law.

Pursuant to the Fair Credit Reporting Act ("FCRA"), we may share information about your Transaction/Experience Information (as defined by the FCRA) with our affiliates and non-affiliated third parties to the extent permitted by law and by our policies.

As required by the USA Patriot Act, we also collect information and take actions necessary to verify your identification.

## Your Right To Opt-Out

If you do not wish for us to share your information with our affiliates, you have the right to opt out at any time. If you wish to opt out, you may do so in any one of the following ways:

  * [Log in to eBranch](https://ebranch.wescom.org/). Click on "Options," then "Promotional Preferences" and make your choice.
  * Print the opt-out form, available online, fill it out and return it to Wescom at 123 South Marengo Avenue, Pasadena , CA 91101. 
  * Or print the opt-out form, fill it out and fax it to 1-866-793-7266. 

Your opt-out will remain effective for five years or until revoked in writing. Please note that even if you opt out, we will continue to share your information to conduct our business as described above, to the extent permitted by law.

## How We Protect Your Information

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural controls that comply with federal regulations to guard your information. We restrict access to your personal information to those employees who need it in order to provide products and services to you. Where appropriate, we use security encoding techniques to protect against unauthorized access to personal records, ensure accuracy and integrity of data, and protect your confidentiality. We provide training to educate employees on the purpose and implementation of procedures related to privacy and the confidentiality of member data.

## Changes To Our Policy

We reserve the right to revise our policy as out business needs change or as the law requires. If we revise our policies, we will provide our members with copies of our new policies at that time.

## Restricting Credit Offers, Direct Mail, and Telemarketing Solicitations

Businesses can obtain information about you from public records such as those available at County Recorders. They may use this information to market their services and sometimes make reference to your Credit Union. Wescom cannot control or restrict the use of publicly available information about you, and we do not authorize these businesses to use our name. However, there are steps you can take to minimize these and other types of direct mail solicitations.

## Credit Solicitations

You may contact credit reporting agencies directly and ask that your name be removed from unsolicited credit offers. By doing this, you will no longer receive credit offers from credit card companies and financial institutions, including Wescom. You may call 1-888-5OPT-OUT or write to:

**Experian**  
Attn: Consumer Services Department  
901 West Bond   
Lincoln, NE 68521

**Equifax**  
P.O. Box 740241  
Atlanta, GA 30374

**TransUnion Name Removal Option**  
P.O. Box 505  
Woodlyn, PA 19094

**Direct Mail and Telemarketing Solicitations**

You may contact the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) and ask that your name be removed from lists used for direct mail and telephone solicitations. This will only eliminate advertising from companies that subscribe to these services. To remove your name from the lists of companies not subscribing to DMA services, you must contact them directly.

## National Do Not Call Registry

To have your phone number added to the National Do Not Call Registry, you may call 1-888-382-1222 or register at donotcall.gov. This should stop most calls, but not necessarily calls from business with which you are a customer.

**Mail Preference Service**  
Direct Marketing Association  
P.O. Box 643  
Carmel, NY 10512

**Telephone Preference Service**  
Direct Marketing Association  
P.O. Box 643  
Carmel, NY 10512

## Consumer Information About Telemarketing 

Federal and State agencies publish information designed to educate you about telemarketing. You may request copies of this information by contacting them directly. Agencies include:

  * **Federal Trade Commission**  
Toll-free 1-877-382-4357  
Straight Talk About Telemarketing  
www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/tmarkg/straight.htm
  * **Federal Communications Commission**  
Toll-free 1-888-225-5322  
Unwanted Telephone Marketing Calls  
http://www.fcc.gov/cgb/consumerfacts/tcpa.html

Fax Advertising: What You Need to Know  
http://www.fcc.gov/cgb/consumerfacts/unwantedfaxes.html

  * **California Department of Consumer Affairs**  
Toll-free 1-800-952-5210  
Basic Facts About Telemarketing  
http://www.dca.ca.gov/r_r/telemarket.htm  

  * **Identity Theft**  
You can learn how to minimize the risk of identity theft on the following government Websites:

Federal Trade Commission Web site:  
www.consumer.gov/idtheft/

Department of Justice Web site:  
www.usdoj.gov/criminal/fraud/idtheft.html

Social Security Administration Web site:  
www.ssa.gov/pubs/idtheft.htm

For questions about our Privacy Policy, you may contact Wescom Credit Union by calling 1-888-4WESCOM (1-888-493-7266) or by writing Wescom Credit Union, P.O. Box 7058, Pasadena, CA 91109-7058. 

|
